<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Getting Started on taskcat workshop</title><link>/00_concepts.html</link><description>Recent content in Getting Started on taskcat workshop</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/00_concepts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>/00_concepts/00_page1.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/00_concepts/00_page1.html</guid><description>What is taskcat? taskcat is a tool that tests AWS CloudFormation templates. It deploys your AWS CloudFormation template in multiple AWS Regions and generates a report with a pass/fail grade for each region. You can specify the regions and number of Availability Zones you want to include in the test, and pass in parameter values from your AWS CloudFormation template. taskcat is implemented as a Python class that you import, instantiate, and run.</description></item><item><title>Config hierarchy</title><link>/00_concepts/00_page2.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/00_concepts/00_page2.html</guid><description>Taskcat uses two config files: Global config and Project config
Project Config This config file provides project-specific configurations.
The project config file is located in the root of your project folder &amp;lt;PROJECT_ROOT&amp;gt;/.taskcat.yml
Since each lab uses the cfn-project directory as the project root, this is where our project-specific taskcat config file will reside.
Global config This config file provides global settings that become defaults for all projects.
The global config file is located in user&amp;rsquo;s home-directory.</description></item><item><title>Parameter Overrides</title><link>/00_concepts/00_page3.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/00_concepts/00_page3.html</guid><description>Parameter Overrides Parameter Overrides were added to taskcat to solve a common problem: we didn&amp;rsquo;t want to add sensitive data (usernames, passwords, tokens) to a git repository. The idea was to store sensitive data outside of a git repository, but still execute a test using this data. To that end, any parameter defined in the global config will take precedence over the same parameter in a project-level config. We use this feature to ensure we&amp;rsquo;re using the appropraite S3 Buckets, keypairs, etc.</description></item></channel></rss>