<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Lab 1 on taskcat workshop</title><link>/10_lab1.html</link><description>Recent content in Lab 1 on taskcat workshop</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/10_lab1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Taskcat config hierarchy</title><link>/10_lab1/10_page1.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/10_lab1/10_page1.html</guid><description>Taskcat config hierarchy Taskcat uses two config files Global config and Project config
Project Config Ths config file provides project specific configuration.
The project config file is located in the root of your project folder &amp;lt;PROJECT_ROOT&amp;gt;/.taskcat.yml
Global config This config file provides global settings that become defaults for all projects.
The global config file is located in the users homedir ~/.taskcat.yml</description></item><item><title>Add a (Project Level) config</title><link>/10_lab1/10_page2.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/10_lab1/10_page2.html</guid><description> Project Config Ths config file provides project specific configuration.
The project config file is located in the root of your project folder &amp;lt;PROJECT_ROOT&amp;gt;/.taskcat.yml
From the vscode file browser navigate to the lab1/,
Open that taskcat.yml
Double click on the file to open them in the ide tabs
@TODO Screen shoot need updated to show appstream</description></item><item><title>- Define project section</title><link>/10_lab1/10_page3.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/10_lab1/10_page3.html</guid><description> Add a project section for the value of name: specify the name of the project folder
project: name: cfn-project</description></item><item><title>Defining tests</title><link>/10_lab1/10_page4.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/10_lab1/10_page4.html</guid><description> Adding test definitions Define a test called mytest and define the template location
Specfiy path to your relative to you project root template: templates/lab1.template.yaml
Optionally you you can set the project_root to a diffrent location if need be:
-p PROJECT_ROOT or --project-root PROJECT_ROOT
tests: mytest: template: templates/lab1.template.yaml</description></item><item><title>- Define regions</title><link>/10_lab1/10_page5.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/10_lab1/10_page5.html</guid><description> Add regions to your test The region: key is optional for tests by default region inherit from the global configuration (We will conver global configs later in this lab) The region parameter takes a list of regions. When defined in a test, taskcat will limit test to those regions
For now only specifiy one region us-east-1
tests: mytest: template: templates/lab1.template.yaml regions: - us-east-1</description></item><item><title>- Define parameters</title><link>/10_lab1/10_page6.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/10_lab1/10_page6.html</guid><description>Add a parameter section to the test add the parameters: set the value of S3BucketName to $[taskcat_autobucket] This will evaulate to the bucket that taskcat creates during execution Hint: Parameter vaules can be dynamically passed to a stack during creation when testing with taskcat. For example: By specifing $[taskcat_autobucket] as the value of S3BucketName we can instruct taskcat to replace value with the name of the bucket that will be created at runtime</description></item><item><title>Execute a taskcat test</title><link>/10_lab1/10_page7.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/10_lab1/10_page7.html</guid><description> Start a test From you vsode terminal change directory to you project root for lab1 (lab_assets/start/lab1/cfn-project)
Under cfn-project you will see the following files
cfn-project ├── lambda_functions ├── templates └── .taskcat.yml From the cfn-project dir run you taskcat testa
taskcat test run Expected output:</description></item><item><title>View test results</title><link>/10_lab1/10_page8.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/10_lab1/10_page8.html</guid><description>Test Results After the test completes you will see a new folder under cfn-project called taskcat_outputs
cfn-project ├── lambda_functions ├── templates ├── .taskcat.yml └── taskcat_outputs/index.html &amp;lt; - (report) open taskcat_outputs/index.html in the your web browser To see the test logs click the View Logs link</description></item></channel></rss>